Hi, in this lesson, I want to talk about some popular use cases of using AI coding
assistance.
So, the first topic I want to cover is that ES system can help us really understand
how our code works, how project works.
You can ask any question about components, about files, about logic and your project.
For example, you can ask, "Please explain me how the authentication works in this
React application."
For example, how the data passes between these components, or you can ask, for example,
to add some GSDO documentation for some hooks, if they're not really cleared to you or you
want to impose the comment in a field code.
The next use case is refactoring React components.
So, you can clean and improve your React code using AI coding assistance.
You can ask a system to improve it and it can split your components or rename probes or
even simplify the logic.
For example, some popular prompts can be like refactoring this large component into smaller
ones.
For example, you can ask, "Redame confusing problems in this form if you use some form
I know for saving a user or saving a payment details," you can ask to refactor the whole
form and it will simplify the variable's name to make it much clear for developers.
You can also ask, simplify a plus logic, for example, for this hook of this function.
Well, the next use case is converting React code to another language of framework.
For example, if you use still legacy application, you can convert your old framework code
to React. For example, if you use that class components, you can ask converted direct hooks,
for example.
Well, if you need, for example, move from React to Vue.js or Angular.
So, you can also ask, help me, of course, component by component to rewrite this code
to support the new framework.
It can help you with building React features.
For example, if you need to build the user authentication, you can quickly implement login
forms, registration page, and even the whole flow with validation in an or handling using
AI assistance.
So, it can build the draft pages for you, of course, you might need to edit it to, I
know, a bit change the structure, a bit correct something, but it can make you draft like
the boy up wait work for you, and you can just edit it in the review.
For example, you can also ask, for example, creating some responsive components like a side
bar, some menus.
If you don't really want to dive into how CSS animation works, how some JavaScript logic
should be written for manual to hide and show it, so you can ask, so the AI assistant
to write it.
I can also ask, help, when you build some, to do least some shopping carts, some, I come
and use cases, yeah, because a lot of people build it and AI has an overview, it has
an overview of how it should be built, so it can recommend you how it should be.
So, like some example, some prompt examples can be like, can you add a user login
form with validation, or can you create responsive navigation bar, for example, can you
build it to do least, and you can mention, so what the storage or state management you
want to support, I think also can help you writing tests for your code.
For example, if you have a lot of components, you can ask, for example, please cover
this, please write unit tests for some hooks, for example, create tests for some form, I
use in my application, you can also mention what libraries you want to use for test coverage,
so it can do the unit testing, it can do also the component testing, some integration testing,
if you need to test how few components works between each other, you can also do some
snapshot testing, if you need to be sure your HTML, for example, some files is not changed
during the updating code, so it's really useful.
You can modernize on legacy record, as I mentioned one of previous examples, if you use
like legacy class components, and you really have experience only working with React hooks,
you can ask so to rewrite it, you can also, for example, ask it to modernize, for example,
if the old project use prop types, you can ask, okay, can you convert it to the TypeScript
interface, as the types, if you don't want to write it manually, it can save a lot of
time for you, so, so you see some prompt examples right here, for example, you can ask
for updating the React dependencies, on small logic is probably not a use case, but if you
want to large projects with a big team, there is some special system which track, if there
is any vulnerabilities in your dependencies, for example, you just need to update because
you want to support up-to-date version, with all the changes and fixes, so you can ask
also a yes system to do that, and it will handle, figure out how to do it for you, so
like a case, if you need upgrade from React 18 to the newer version, for example, you need
to update some React libraries, or if you want to migrate from some state-to-one, state-management
to another one, so you see, it can update packages, it can test everything works, of course,
we need to recheck it by ourselves because AI can do mistakes, and it do it quite often,
so, but it's at least given us idea how, what commands we should do, like, what plan we
should follow, so with some draft code changes, and we can test it and just align it a bit
or change, so, it can also help us fix some breaking changes, say, for example, we upgrade
in from some major version of the library, and we don't know what was really changing
the library, so he can try to fix, do some fixes for us.
If you need to debug code of power application, for example, we have some performance issues,
we can ask, okay, why is this component keep rendering, and yes system will give you some
ideas of why it's happening, and also do the suggestions how to fix it.
For example, if you have some bugs in the state management, you need to debug, okay, some
side effects, some component lifecycle, you can ask some AI system to help you.
For example, if you need to fix some memory leaks, or clean up some function event
listeners, so you can always ask any of you, provide you some idea and code suggestions.
Another really use case, it's learning a React to write in the documentation.
For example, if some features any technologies new for you, you can use AI assistance
to help you dive into it.
For example, I know to give you some plan, a step-by-step how we should learn it.
For example, provide some explanation how some hooks work, so what's the difference between
some functions or methods?
In another case, it's writing documentation.
You can ask to write the GSDOC documentation in your files, or you can just ask to write
some documentation and just paste it in some very Google Docs on Confluence, like ask
to document your code.
It also can generate some readme files, how to run and type your project because it's
small of the context, so it can help you with it.
I hope this use cases was useful for you, and now you have more idea of what you can do
with AI assistance, why you can use them what prompt examples you can write to work faster
and easier, and see you in the next lesson.